Authenticate with a GitHub host.

The default hostname is `github.com`. This can be overridden using the `--hostname`
flag.

The default authentication mode is a web-based browser flow. After completion, an
authentication token will be stored securely in the system credential store.
If a credential store is not found or there is an issue using it gh will fallback
to writing the token to a plain text file. See `gh auth status` for its
stored location.

Alternatively, use `--with-token` to pass in a personal access token (classic) on standard input.
The minimum required scopes for the token are: `repo`, `read:org`, and `gist`.
Take care when passing a fine-grained personal access token to `--with-token`
as the inherent scoping to certain resources may cause confusing behaviour when interacting with other
resources. Favour setting `GH_TOKEN` for fine-grained personal access token usage.

Alternatively, gh will use the authentication token found in environment variables.
This method is most suitable for "headless" use of gh such as in automation. See
`gh help environment` for more info.

To use gh in GitHub Actions, add `GH_TOKEN: ${{ github.token }}` to `env`.

The git protocol to use for git operations on this host can be set with `--git-protocol`,
or during the interactive prompting. Although login is for a single account on a host, setting
the git protocol will take effect for all users on the host.

Specifying `ssh` for the git protocol will detect existing SSH keys to upload,
prompting to create and upload a new key if one is not found. This can be skipped with
`--skip-ssh-key` flag.

For more information on OAuth scopes, see
<https://docs.github.com/en/developers/apps/building-oauth-apps/scopes-for-oauth-apps/>.


USAGE
  gh auth login [flags]

FLAGS
  -c, --clipboard             Copy one-time OAuth device code to clipboard
  -p, --git-protocol string   The protocol to use for git operations on this host: {ssh|https}
  -h, --hostname string       The hostname of the GitHub instance to authenticate with
      --insecure-storage      Save authentication credentials in plain text instead of credential store
  -s, --scopes strings        Additional authentication scopes to request
      --skip-ssh-key          Skip generate/upload SSH key prompt
  -w, --web                   Open a browser to authenticate
      --with-token            Read token from standard input

INHERITED FLAGS
  --help   Show help for command

EXAMPLES
  # Start interactive setup
  $ gh auth login
  
  # Open a browser to authenticate and copy one-time OAuth code to clipboard
  $ gh auth login --web --clipboard
  
  # Authenticate against github.com by reading the token from a file
  $ gh auth login --with-token < mytoken.txt
  
  # Authenticate with specific host
  $ gh auth login --hostname enterprise.internal

LEARN MORE
  Use `gh <command> <subcommand> --help` for more information about a command.
  Read the manual at https://cli.github.com/manual
  Learn about exit codes using `gh help exit-codes`
  Learn about accessibility experiences using `gh help accessibility`

